Two former CIA agents who are now
YouTubers get into a heated debate mid
podcast and this one gets very
interesting.
>> I Why are you working
with Russian state media? Oh, because
I've got five kids and nobody's beating
a path to my door to give me work.
>> We've seen many people in this position
being accused of this very thing. He
does something unusual and and just owns
it and claims, "Look, I have kids to
feed. The government threw me in prison
for exposing the waterboarding program
under Obama."
>> That is exactly the foundation for
how Russian covert influence operations
happen.
>> Aw, poor CIA.
>> Andrew is kind of taken aback by this.
the American government. What have
they done for me? What have they done
for my children?
>> Do you really want to violate my rights?
>> really not know the answer to that?
>> Come on, man.
>> He doesn't land a single blow in this
entire interaction. This is a really
interesting game being played here. I
would be interested to know how people
feel about this. I don't know what the
right answer is.
>> It was the CIA that put me in prison.
What in the world do I owe the CIA?
>> decisions that put you in prison.
>> lawbreaking that put me in prison.
>> your choice to highlight the CIA's
lawbreaking to media that put you in
prison.
>> There we go.
>> And there it is. That is the moment that
Andrew lost this thing. It was your
decision to highlight the CIA's
lawbreaking. When is it okay for a
whistleblower to blow the whistle?
>> Government, I think or the agency maybe
would have been perfectly happy if I
starved to death from lack of work or
ended up at McDonald's.
And uh
and I worked hard to rebuild my life.
Uh the only people who offered me a job
were the Russians.
>> That seems to be John Kiriakou's
message. More information is good. I'm
going to use the platform that's
available to me. It's up to the people
listening to think for themselves.
>> Your children, they live every day under
the protection of the United States.
They have all the benefits of American
citizens. They Your You get to enjoy
You're here on an American podcast. You
flew on American Airlines. You're
staying in American protected hotel.
You're You're You're The police officers
driving around the streets right now.
All of these people are contributing to
the freedoms that you have.
>> Oh, wow.
>> All of them.
>> Wow.
>> And you're sitting here saying
>> a true believer.
>> I'm a true believer in the fact that we
We have to serve the American
dream. We have to serve the American
purpose. That's what we're here to do.
>> what I'm doing by opposing the American
government.
>> These two guys couldn't be more
different in their perspective on this
topic, which is what makes this
interaction so interesting.
>> You don't oppose the American government
by making yourself a voice for Russian
state media.
>> Why not?
>> Because you're not talking out about the
American government, first of all. What
you're talking out about is Putin's
invasion of Ukraine.
>> No, I talk about the American government
every single day.
>> So, whatever Whoever you're you're
speaking to, you are a You are giving
credibility and authority and and and
you're you're loaning all of your hard
work
to Russian media for paycheck.
>> I I don't see how that's a a problem.
>> Isn't it a question?
>> you didn't come from CIA, they wouldn't
care about you.
>> This Everyday Spy guy, Andrew, he's
selling his toolkit, his courses to
teach people how to use espionage.
>> If they don't buy his course, they might
be victims to espionage. You're making
money off of working for the CIA as
well.
>> I created a 3-minute CIA-style quiz to
help you unlock your secret
psychological advantage and identify
your hidden blind spot. This test was
developed to help you weaponize your
natural-born gifts and use them to get
ahead of 99% of people.
>> So.
>> So, you're borrowing the authority of
CIA. That's what makes you valuable to
Russian media.
>> No, I'm able to expose crimes that I
that I witnessed in the CIA, sure.
And and maybe that gives me a little bit
more cachet.
>> John Kiriakou separate of CIA would not
be of interest to Russian media. So,
what makes John Kiriakou
>> true.
>> I would argue so what? Our narrative is
what determines how the world views us.
There's nothing we can do about that.
>> Yeah, okay.
So, I I was one of the government's
leading experts on the Middle East.
>> Without the government, you wouldn't be
>> If I had been at the State Department,
or if I had been in academia, I'd still
be an expert on the Middle East.
>> You everything that you're pulling
everything from government, man. You're
>> So, what?
>> So,
>> I don't I don't see how you think I owe
the government something.
>> you owe the government anything. I'm
just saying that the ideals that you
had, you must have had in 2019 84, 1889.
>> Yeah.
>> You must have compromised on those
ideals. You must have at some point
>> Isn't Isn't questioning the government
and holding the government accountable
something that the United States was
founded on?
>> I don't know the answer to that.
>> Of course it is.
>> What?
>> This is where it goes off the rails.
This is the real question at the heart
of this debate.
>> How? How?
>> Isn't that in the Constitution?
>> If you've ever been curious about buying
and investing in crypto, Bitcoin, stable
coins, USAT, or even gold-backed stable
coins, but maybe you felt like it was
too complicated. Rumble Wallet is an
easy way to get started. You can buy,
sell, and manage your cryptocurrencies
all in one place, and the app is super
straightforward. What makes Rumble
Wallet really unique is that you can use
it to tip your favorite creators and
support the Freedom First Community that
has been built on Rumble. Getting
started is simple. Just download the
Rumble Wallet app, sign up with your
existing Rumble account, no need for a
new login. Complete a few security
steps, and you're set up in a few
minutes. You can start with a few
dollars, and with MoonPay built into
Rumble Wallet, you can easily buy crypto
using your credit or debit card or bank
wire. So, if you've been thinking about
the advantages of crypto, download
Rumble Wallet now. Click my link in the
description or search Rumble Wallet in
your app store. Download Rumble Wallet
today and move your assets to where they
belong, in your hands and in your
control.
>> Isn't that in the Constitution?
I I don't know the answer to that
either. Is there a Can somebody flag
where there's any mention of individual
accountability to the government? Cuz
I'm pretty sure that's why we are a
representative democracy. It is our
representatives who are supposed to do
that.
>> What if you do encounter something that
is corrupt within the government and you
are working for, say, the CIA? I'd be
interested to know who do you think is
right here?
>> Not us. What we're supposed to do is be
really good at what we do and
vote in meaningful representatives to
represent the constituents in all forms
of government. It is not our job to
meddle in government.
>> That's the big red flag for me. Anytime
someone is arguing for blind obedience,
no matter what, that is the death of
critical thought. That's where he's
going to lose this.
>> We have an obligation
forevermore. We will never be normal
citizens.
>> I think that's nonsense.
>> You can think whatever you want to
think.
>> I really do. If you are a private
citizen,
your loyalty is to yourself.
>> Reminds me of this quote, that which I
have alone protects me. I think there is
some wisdom to that. I write about this
in the book that's coming out soon. Is
when you are in a career path and
suddenly you are thrown out of it or
thrown under it,
you are on your own. So, I can
understand what that feels like.
>> Within the confines of the law, of
course, and the Constitution.
But I don't owe the government anything.
>> I'm not saying you owe the government
anything. I'm saying that that
we have a responsibility, we have an
obligation to recognize that we can
become tools for our adversaries against
the very things that we believe in,
specifically because of our affiliation
with
government organizations.
>> The team you thought you were part of is
now trying to take you down and you're
fighting for your own what feels like
your own survival. And in those moments,
that which you have alone is what
protects you.
>> I sit in front of a microphone every day
and I talk about what's in the papers.
That's my job. It's a 2-hour news show.
That's it. And then I get up and I go
home.
>> You talk about your opinions, also.
>> Yeah, my opinions aren't a secret.
Right? We all have these personal
ideologies.
>> I I'm just
I am
I guess I'm sad. I'm sad for
>> But then where do you draw the line? Do
you Do you not give an interview to a
Turkish outlet?
>> If you're going to support an adversary
uh you can justify it however you
choose.
>> I don't support the adversary.
The adversary offered me an outlet
that I gladly accepted.
>> a bare minimum, your outlet generates
revenue for an adversary.
>> Ad revenue on a YouTube channel, okay. I
get I mean you could make that argument.
>> It's a government-sponsored
uh radio. I mean there's no advertising,
there's no revenue stream. It's like
Voice of America.
>> It's If if there is no actual money
changing hands, I would be surprised
because there's always got to be money
that changes hands somewhere. And you're
also talking about
>> what that means.
>> There's always money. There's always a
funding source, there's always a donor
base, there's always a There's always an
exchange of value. Nothing is free.
>> a It's a government-funded
radio network.
>> Funded by which government?
>> The Russian government.
>> The Russian government funds a radio
channel
>> Yeah.
>> for which audience?
>> For the American audience.
>> For the American people using the voice
of a CIA officer.
>> Yes.
>> And you don't see a problem with that?
>> Absolutely none.
>> Do we do that in other countries?
>> Of course we do. It's called the
Voice of America.
>> It's called the Voice of America.
>> influence. It's the same thing
that that Tucker Carlson did with
Vladimir Putin.
>> So you think it's So how do you So
>> What?
>> I think But what RT is paying for
is for a channel of of media uh
exposure into the United States.
>> Good. Maybe I can educate somebody.
I'll take it.
7 days a week.
>> [laughter]
>> I will take it.
>> This does go to the freedom of speech
debate. It's an interesting question,
one that I do not have the answer to,
but it's worth [music] thinking about.
The ideal outcome is more likely to come
from people genuinely trying to pursue
what they believe to be right.